Josh Woodcock // Full Stack Software Engineer

832-247-8742 // josh@j0w0.com // github.com/j0w00 // www.j0w0.com // www.linkedin.com/in/jrwoodcock

Full Stack Software Engineer that enjoys finding creative solutions to complex problems by utilizing front- and backend technologies. I enjoy engineering the process just as much as writing the code. While I am analytical and get into the finer details, my design experience enables me to think more creatively and bring a unique perspective to the team.

Skills: HTML, CSS / SCSS, JavaScript, React.js, Node.js, MongoDB, Express, Python, Django, PostgreSQL, Amazon AWS, Heroku, Google OAuth, Passport.js, Google Maps API, AJAX, JSON, Websockets, Bootstrap, jQuery, Wordpress, PHP, MySQL, GitHub, Homebrew, npm, RESTful APIs, Git, Stripe, Twilio, WooCommerce, Photoshop, Illustrator.

Experience

Full Stack Software Engineer

General Assembly | July 2020-October 2020 | Austin, Texas (Remote)

 Gained hands-on experience working with the latest in front- and back-end web technologies through General Assembly's full-time, Software Engineering Immersive.

Front-End / UX Developer

Remedy | January 2019-July 2020 | Austin, Texas

- Streamlined web application for urgent care bookings that saw an increase of appointments by over 1000% and helped win two stages of VC funding for the start-up.
- Developed admin utilities to help service coordinators better assist patients during the scheduling process.

MIS Web Developer

Ford Audio-Video | January 2017-January 2019 | Austin, Texas

- Developed a complete overhaul of the company's WordPress website, allowing easier content management.
- Created and managed marketing event web applications for event registration, check in, lead tracking, and payments.
- Developed business software and helped maintain the company's Intranet on WordPress.

Digital Media Marketing Coordinator

Ford Audio-Video | July 2014-January 2017 | Austin, Texas

 Oversaw the production of all email campaigns and web graphics, as well as maintained corporate website content, event landing pages, and company Intranet. Value was seen in my programming abilities and I was promoted to the Engineering team as MIS Web Developer.

Contract Web Developer

COMNIO | July 2016-May 2017 | Austin, Texas

Designed and developed micro-sites and online registration/contest forms for clients utilizing WordPress and Bootstrap.

Education

Texas State University

Bachelor of Fine Arts, Communication Design | San Marcos, Texas | May 2014

Queens College

National Student Exchange, Graphic Design | Flushing, New York | 2012–2013